Mss.B.P31
American Philosophical Society
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1675-1960; 27 boxes, 8.5 linear feet
  - Letter to [Mrs. Martha McGlathery Peale], April 18, 1839; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Peale, Edmund, 1805-1851
    Bedford, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. (see Peale-Sellers Papers.) Concerning her trunk which has been shipped.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Martha McGlathery Peale], April 18, 1839; 12-1/2x7-3/4; Stockton, Eliza Ferguson Peale, 1799-1876
    A.L. 2p. (see Peale-Sellers Papers.) News of family and friends.
  - Letter to Rubens Peale, Philadelphia, June 22, 1839; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Peale, Edmund, 1805-1851
    A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Peale-Sellers Papers.) Business. Concerning "ma[m]a".
  - Letter to Mrs. [Sophonisba Peale] Sellers, Philadelphia, July 2, 1839; 10x8; Harrold, Elizabeth Coleman Sellers, 1810-
    Birmingham, A.L.S. 4p.,add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Mrs. Martha [McGlathery] Peale, Philadelphia, July 26, 1839; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Stockton, Eliza Ferguson Peale, 1799-1876
    A.L.S. 4p.,add. (see Peale-Sellers Papers.) Friendly letter. Concerning the family and self.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale] Sellers, Philadelphia, July 29, 1839; 10x8; Harrold, Elizabeth Coleman Sellers, 1810-
  - Letter to Messrs. Sellers, Aug. 6, 1839; 10-1/2x8; Brown, David Paul, 1795-1872
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Asks payment of bills.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Sophonisba Peale] Sellers, Philadelphia, Aug. 18, 21, 1839; 10x8; Harrold, Elizabeth Coleman Sellers, 1810-
    Birmingham, A.L.S.with initials. 4p.,add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Mrs. S[ophonisba Peale] Sellers, Philadelphia, Aug. 20, 1839; 10x8; Bolmar, A. (Anthony), 1797-1861
    West Chester, A.L.S. 1p.end add.,end.and enc.of 1p. Encloses statement for Coleman's schooling. Vol II p. 55
  - Letter to Elizabeth Hill, Philadelphia, Aug. 23, 1839; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
    West Chester, A.L.S. 2p.and add. Concerning school.
  - Letter to Mrs. Sophonisba [Angusciola Peale] Sellers, Philadelphia, Sept. 9, 1839; 12-1/2x7-3/4; Stockton, Eliza Ferguson Peale, 1799-1876
    A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Peale-Sellers Papers.) Family news.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Sophonisba Peale] Sellers, Philadelphia, Sept. 19, 1839; 9x7-1/2; Harrold, Elizabeth Coleman Sellers, 1810-
    Birmingham, A.L. 4p.,add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Mrs. S[ophonisba Peale] Sellers, Philadelphia, Sept. 23, 1839; 10x8; Bolmar, A. (Anthony), 1797-1861
    West Chester, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Concerning Coleman's education. vol IIp.55
  - Letter to Mrs. [Sophonisba Peale] Sellers, Philadelphia, Oct. 15, 1839; 9x7-1/2; Harrold, Alfred, d. 1845
    Birmingham, A.L.S. 4p.,add. Business of the Sellers family.
  - Letter to Mrs. Geo[rge] Escol [Rachel Brooks Parrish] Sellers, Philadelphia, Oct. 15, 1839; 10x8; Sellers, George Escol
    A.L.S. 8p.,add. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Describes his trip from Philadelphia to Cincinnati.
  - Letter to Mrs. Geo[rge] Escol [Rachel Brooks Parrish] Sellers, Philadelphia, Oct. 20, 1839; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, George Escol
    Cleaveland [sic], A.L.S. 4p.,add. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Describes his trip to Cleveland.
  - Letter to Mrs. Geo[rge] Escol [Rachel Brooks Parrish] Sellers, Philadelphia, Oct. 21, 1839; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, George Escol
    A.L. 8p.,add. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning his trip in the Mid-West.
  - Letter to Rembrant Peale, Oct. 23, 1839; Holden, Isaac
  - Letter to Mrs. Geo[rge] Escol [Rachel Brooks Parrish] Sellers, Philadelphia, Oct. 24, 1839; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, George Escol
    Detroit, A.L. 8p.,add. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Wishes to hear from her. Concerning the Mid-West.
  - Letter to Mrs. Geo[rge] Escol [Rachel Parrish] Sellers, Philadelphia, Nov. 6, 1839; 9-3/4x8; Sellers, George Escol
    South Bend, A.L.S. 4p.,add. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Describes the Mid-West.
  - Letter to Mrs. Geo[rge] Escol [Rachel Brooks Parrish] Sellers, Philadelphia, Nov. 10, 1839; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, George Escol
    Chicago, A.L.S. 8p.,add. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Describes his visit in the Mid-West.
  - Letter to Mrs. Martha [McGlathery] Peale, Philadelphia, Nov. 22, 1839; 12-1/2x7-3/4; Stockton, Eliza Ferguson Peale, 1799-1876
    A.L.S. 4p.,add. (see Peale-Sellers Papers.) Has moved and like the new house. News of family and friends.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Sophonisba Peale] Sellers, Philadelphia, Dec. 10, 1839; 10x8; Harrold, Elizabeth Coleman Sellers, 1810-
    New York, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Mutilated. Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Letter to Hannah Sellers Hill, Dec. 25, Jan. 1, [183-?]; 7-3/4x6-1/2; Sellers, Ann Ash, d. 1856
  - Letter to [B.] Frankiln Peale, Philadelphia, April 5, 1840; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    New Zealand, A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Peale papers.No.10.) Describes wreck of the Peacock on ice-bergs.
  - Letter to Charles W. Peale, Pottsville, July 19, 1840; 10x8; Peale, Rubens, 1784-1865
    New York, A.L.S. 4p.,add.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Business conditions in New York. Paternal advice.
  - Letter to Charles W. Peale, Pottsville, July 28, 1840; 10x8; Peale, Rubens, 1784-1865
    New York, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Lists apparatus and prices it. Tells him to stay as school-teacher, for business is bad in New York.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Elizabeth Coleman Sellers Harrold], Sept. 3, 1840; 9x7-1/4; Harrold, E. B.
    A.L.S. 4P. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to George Escol Sellers, Philadelphia, Sept. 9, 1840; 10x7-3/4; Deane, F. B., Jr.
    Richmond, A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Will help him financially, if he comes to Richmond.
  - Letter to C[harles] W. Peale, Pottsville, Sept. 30, 1840; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Hinchman, Howard
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Politics is causing all disturbance in Philadelphia.
  - Letter to Charles Wil[l]son Peale, New York, Oct. 23, 1840; 10x8; Webb, Rebecca
    A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Will visit New York and asks him to meet her.
  - Letter to Mrs. Harriet [Friel] Peale, Pot[t]sville, Nov. 8, 1840; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Shay, Sarah
    A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Concerning her friends and life in Lebanon.
  - Letter to Charles W. Peale, Nov. 21, 1840; 10x8; Hinchman, Howard
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Social life of Philadelphia.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Elizabeth Coleman Sellers] Harrold, Philadelphia, Dec. 11, 1840; 9x7-1/4; Harrold, W. (Box 8)
    Edgebaxton, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Mrs. S[ophonisba Peale] Sellers, Philadelphia, Jan. 12, 1841; 10x8; Bolmar, A. (Anthony), 1797-1861 (Box 9)
    West Chester, A.L.S. 2p.,add.,end.and enc.of 1p. Sends statement for Coleman's education Note IIp.55
  - Letter to M. B. Hope, Jan. 15, 1841; Peale, Rembrandt, 1778-1860
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s W. Peale, New York, Jan. 18, 1841; 10x8; Bright, Michael
    Pottsville, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Peale Papers. Mills collection.) Social life in Pottsville. Business.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Angusciola Peale Sellers], Jan., 1841; 10x8; Robinson, Angelica Kaufmann Peale, 1775-1853
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) News of her family and relations.
  - Invitation to Mary Bunting and Margaret Coleman to attend the funeral of Elizabeth G. Harrold., Feb. 22, 1841; Unidentified
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s W. Peale, New York, Feb. 25, 1841; 10x7-3/4; Bright, Michael
    A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Social news. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to C[harles] W. Peale, New York, March 20, 1841; 10x8; Bell, John G.
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Is delighted that is opening a store and will help him all he can.
  - Letter to C[harles] W. Peale, New York, March 23, 1841; 9-3/4x8; Bell, John G.
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Concerning a fat girl for the Museum. Concerning prints of giraffes.
  - Letter to Charles W. Peale, New York, March 29, 1841; 10x7-3/4; Bright, Michael
    Pottsville, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Local news. Business is dull.
  - Letter to C[harles] W. Peale, New York, March 31, 1841; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Hinchman, Howard
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Is sorry he has delayed in writing. Glad he is in business.
  - Note to ----, April 23, 1841; 2x7-3/4; Sellers, Anna E.
    A.N.S.with initials. 1p. Friendly note.
  - Letter to Franklin Peale, May 25, 1841; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
  - Letter to C[harles] W. Peale, New York, June 16, 1841; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Bright, Michael
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale Papers. Mills collection.) News of his friends in Pottsville.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Escol Sellers, Philadelphia, June 22, 1841; 10-1/4x8-1/4; Cope, Herman, 1789-1869
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Asks for settlement of debt to the Bank of the United States.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, West Chester, June 26, 1841; 12-1/2x7-3/4; Sellers, George, 1768-1853
    Upper Darby, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Mutilated. Friendly letter. Relates anecdote of Benjamin Rush
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s W. Peale, New York, July 21, 1841; 10x7-3/4; Bright, Michael
    A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) News of Pottsville friends.
  - Letter to Rubens Peale, July 22, 1841; 7" x 9"; Sigourney, L. H. (Lydia Howard), 1791-1865
    Hartford, A.L.S. 2p.and add., end. Mutilated. Seeks advice on exhibition case for some South American birds.
  - Letter to C[harles] W. Peale, New York, Aug. 5, 1841; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Hinchman, Howard
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Peale Papers. Mills collection.) Has visited Washington. Had a letter of introduction to John Quincy Adams.
  - Letter to Mrs. Titian [Eliza Cecilia Laforgue] Peale, Aug. 12, 1841; 10x8; Peale, Rosalba Carriera, 1799-1874
    Philadelphia, Oakland, A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Peale papers.No.10.) Scolds her for not writing. Friendly letter. Inquires for Titian.
  - Letter to Charles W. Peale, New York, Aug. 31, 1841; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Bright, Michael
    A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) News of Pottsville friends.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Escol Sellers, Oct. 3, 1841; 10x7-1/2; Upper Darby Institute
    A.L.S.:Daniel Rhoads. 1p.and add. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Forwards resolutions.
  - Letter to Edward B. Chapman, St.Louis, Oct. 16, 1841; 10x8-1/4; Darlington, Edward, 1795-1884
    Chester, Pa., A.L.S 1p.and add. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Introduces George Escol Sellers.
  - Letter to Charles W. Peale, New York, Oct. 21, 1841; 10x7-3/4; Bright, Michael
    Pottsville, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) News of friends in Pottsville.
  - Letter to Franklin Peale, Philadelphia, Oct. 30, 1841; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    San Francisco, A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Peale papers. No.10.) Printed in part: Poesch. APS Memoirs, vol. 52, 88.
  - Letter to Commander A. Bigelow, Nov. 10, 1841; 12-1/2x8; Forrest, French, 1796-1866
    Callo Bay, L. 1p.and end. Copy. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Dismisses him of his command.
  - Letter to Charles W. Peale, New York, Dec. 23, 1841; 10x7-3/4; Bright, Michael
    A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) News of friends in Pottsville.
  - Letter to [George] E[scol] Sellers, Cincinnati, Dec. 24, 1841; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Ohio Mechanics' Institute
    L. 1p.and add. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Presents him with ticket of admission to lectures, etc.
  - Letter to Rembrandt Peale, [1841]; 10x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Peale papers.) Concerning a possible lease with the APS and the Museum.
  - Letter to Elizabeth S[ellers] Hill, Chester Co., Jan. 23, 1842; 9-3/4x8; Hill, Hannah Sellers
    Mill Bank, A.L.S.: Mother, Aunt Ann, and Peter Hill. 3p.and add. Family news.
  - Letter to Ann Sellers, Mill Bank, Jan. 26, 1842; 9-3/4x8; Sellers, Charles, 1806-1898
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Letter to Charles W. Peale, New York, Feb. 2, 1842; 10x7-3/4; Bright, Michael
  - Letter to Elizabeth S[ellers] Hill, Chester Co., Feb.6, 1842; 9-3/4x8; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Elizabeth S[ellers] Hill, Chester Co., Feb. 12, 1842; 10x8; Sellers, Sarah Ann
    Millbourne, A.L.S. 2p.and add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Elizabeth S[ellers] Hill, Chester Co., Feb. 22, 1842; 9-3/4x8; Hill, Hannah Sellers
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 3p.and add.and P.S.by Ann [Sellers].Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Letter to Elizabeth S[ellers] Hill, Chester Co., Feb. 23, 1842; 10-1/2x8; Cadwallader, E.
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. Friendly letter. vol II p. 61
  - Letter to Benjamin Silliman, Feb. 26, 1842; Peale, Charles Willson, 1821-1871
  - Letter to Charles W. Peale, New York, March 2, 1842; 11x7-1/2; Bright, Michael
    Pottsville, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) New of friends in Pottsville.
  - Letter to Peter Hill, Philadelphia, March 2, 1842; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Huddleson, Elizabeth Sellers Hill
    East Whiteland, A.L.S. 2p.and add.and end.of 1p. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Mrs.] Elizabeth S. Hill [Huddleson], March 19, 1842; 9-3/4x8; Hill, Nathan Sellers
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Newsy family letter.
  - Letter to [Mrs.] Elizabeth S[ellers] Hill [Huddleson], March 27, 1842; 9-3/4x8; Hill, Peter, -1857
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) News of the family and of events in the neighborhood.
  - Letter to Charles W. Peale, New York, March 30, 1842; 10x8; Bright, Michael
    A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) News of gossip and friends in Pottsville.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s W. Peale, New York, April 13, 1842; 10x8; Bright, Michael
    Pottsville, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Needs money badly.
  - Letter to Elizabeth Sellers Hill Huddleston, April 30, 1842; Kite, Anna Maria
  - Letter to Elizabeth S[ellers] Hill, May 12, 1842; 9-3/4x8; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
    Mill Bank, A.L. 3p.and add.with P.S.by H[annah] S[ellers] Hill. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Elizabeth S[ellers] Hill, Chester Co., May 22, 1842; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 2p.and add.and P.S.by H[annah] S[ellers] Hill. Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Letter to Elizabeth S[ellers] Hill, Chester Co., June 10, 1842; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Family news. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Elizabeth S[ellers] Hill [Huddleson], Chester Co., June 13, 1842; 10x7-3/4; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 2p.and add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Elizabeth S[ellers] Hill,Chester Co., June 19, 1842; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Hill, Hannah Sellers
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 1p.and add.with P.S.by Ann [Sellers]. Mutilated.Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Letter to Charles Wil[l]son Peale, Flushing, Long Island, June 22, 1842; 10x8; Pitman, Thomas D.
    New York, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) News of friends in Pottsville.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s W. Peale, June 26, 1842; 10x8; Reason, Patrick Henry, 1816-1898
    New York, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Will pay for shells as soon as possible.
  - Letter to Elizabeth S[ellers] Hill, Chester Co., June 26, 1842; 10x8; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 2p.and add. Family letter. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to C[harles] W. Peale, July 13, 1842; 10x7-1/2; Peale, Rubens, 1784-1865
    Pottsville, A.L.S. 4p.,add.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Offers farms for his settling on.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s W. Peale, Flushing, July 27, 1842; 10x7-3/4; Wheatley, Charles M. (Charles Moore), 1822-1882
    New York, A.L.S.with initials. 2p.and add.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Offers to purchase his natural history specimens.
  - Letter to Charles W. Peale, Flushing, July 29, 1842; 10x8; Wheatley, Charles M. (Charles Moore), 1822-1882
    New York, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Would like to exchange minerals.
  - Letter to Titian [R.] Peale, Philadelphia, July, 1842; 10x7-1/2; Stockton, Eliza Ferguson Peale, 1799-1876
    Mt. Vernon, Ohio, A.L.S. 1p.and add. and P.S.of 1p.by John C. Stockton. (see Peale papers. No.10.) Congratulates him on his return from the Wilkes expedition. Introduces H.B. Curtis.
  - Letter to Elizabeth S[ellers] Hill, Chester, Aug. 1, 1842; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Martha
    Sharon, A.L.S. 2p.and add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Mrs.] Elizabeth S[ellers] Hill [Huddleson], Aug. 21, 1842; 9-3/4x8; Hill, Nathan Sellers
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Tells of fishing excursion and accident which occurred.
  - Letter to [Mrs.] Hannah S[ellers] Hill, Chester Co., Aug. 28, 1842; 12-1/2x8; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
    Mill Bank, A.L. 4p.,add. Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Letter to Mrs. Harriet Peale, Sept. 4, 1842; 9x7-1/4, 5-1/4x6-1/2; Phreaner, Elmina
    Lebanon, A.L.S. 2p.and add.with enc.of poem. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Plans to leave Lebanon.
  - Letter to Elizabeth S[ellers] Hill, Chester Co., Sept. 11, 1842; 10x7-3/4; Watson, Sarah
    A.L.S. 3p.and add. Friendly letter. vol II p.65
  - Letter to M[ary] Florida Peale, Emmitsburg, Sept., 1842; 10x7-3/4; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p.and 2p.P.S.by "Mother" and add. (see Peale papers. No. 10.) Is sending some shells. Wilkes trial. United Bowmen contest. Family news.
  - Letter to Is[rael Jackson?] Amies, Philadelphia, Oct. 6, 1842; 9-3/4x8; Bancroft, G. M.
    Boston, A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Glad to hear from him. Enjoyed meeting Mr. Eckendoff and comments on their meetings.
  - Letter to C[harles] E. [sic] and Geo[rge Escol] Sellers, Oct. 16, 1842; 5x8; Wright, J. C.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. Mutilated. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Legal matter.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s W. Peale, Pottsville, Nov. 2, 1842; 10x8; Jenkins, William A.
    Richmond, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Informs him of land in Virginia which is owned by Rubens Peale.
  - Letter to [Mary] Florida Peale, Emmitsburg, Md., Nov. 6, 1842; 10x7-1/2; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p.with P.S.by "mother" and add. (see Peale papers. No.10.) Family news. Hopes to prepare papers for the Wilkes expedition.
  - Notification to C. W. Peale of his appointment as school teacher, Nov. 20, 1842; Hudson, John
  - Letter to Samuel Sellers, Nov. 20, 1842; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, James, Jr.
    Springton, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Rubens Peale, Dec. 1, 1842; Sunderland, La Roy, 1802-1885
  - Letter to Rubens Peale, Dec. 19, 1842; Sunderland, La Roy, 1802-1885
  - Letter to Rubens Peale, Dec. 27, 1842; Sunderland, La Roy, 1802-1885
  - Letter to Ann Sellers, Upper Darby, Dec. 28, 1842; 10x8; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
    Northumberland, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Mrs.] Hannah S[ellers] Hill, Chester Co., Dec. 20, Jan. 1, 1842, 1843; 10x8; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 4p.,add. Family news. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to ----, Jan. 1, 1843; 10x8; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
    A.L. 2p. Incomplete. Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Letter to Samuel Sellers, Jan. 17, 1843; 10x7-1/2; Sellers, James, Jr.
    Springton, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Letter to Samuel Sellers, Feb. 1, 1843; 10x7-1/2; Sellers, James, Jr.
    A.L.S. 4p.,add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to George Sellers, Chester Co., Feb. 3, 1843; 10x7-1/2; Sellers, Cyrus C.
    A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Samuel Sellers, Feb. 7, 1843; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, James, Jr.
    Springton, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Sarah Pennock, Liddonfield, Feb. 18, 1843; 8-1/2x7-3/4; Sellers, James, Jr.
    Springton, A.L.S. 1p. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Samuel Sellers, March 22, 1843; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, James, Jr.
  - Letter to Titian R. Peale, Washington, March 23, 1843; 10x7-1/2; Peale, Augustin Runyon, 1819-1856
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Peale papers. No.10.) Asks for help in finding a position.
  - Letter to Ann Sellers, Philadelphia, July 10, 1843; 10x7-1/2; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
    Northumberland, A.L.S. 4p.and add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Mrs.] Hannah S[ellers] Hill, Pennsgrove, Sept. 10, 1843; 10x8; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 2p.,add. Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Invitation to Peter Hill to attend the funeral of William Hill, Sept. 26, 1843; 7-1/2x5; Hill, J. Harrison
  - Letter to Anna Sellers, Philadelphia, Nov. 12, 1843; 10x8; Sellers, Charles, 1806-1898
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 4p.,add. Friendly letter. Concerning J.Q.Adams in Cincinnati.
  - Letter to Elizabeth S[ellers] Hill, Pennsgrove, Jan. 1, 1844; 10x7-1/2; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Partly in pencil. Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Letter to Mrs. T. R. [Eliza Cecilia Lafargue] Peale, Jan. 10, 1844; 10x7-3/4; Peale, Franklin, 1795-1870
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and receipted. (see Peale papers. No.10.) Asks for Museum books.
  - Letter to [Mrs.] Hannah S[ellers] Hill, Pennsgrove, Jan. 21, 1844; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 4p.,add. Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Escol Sellers, Philadelphia, Jan. 28, 1844; 10x8; Sellers, Rachel Brooks Parrish
    Cincinnati, A.L. 3p.and add. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Has turned bitter cold. Hopes he is safe and well. News of friends.
  - Letter to Mrs. Sophonisba [Peale] Sellers, Philadelphia, Jan. 29-31, 1844; 10x7-3/4; Harrold, Alfred, d. 1845
  - Letter to Mrs. [Sophonisba Peale] Sellers, Jan. 30, 1844; 8x5; Harrold, E. B.
    Edgbaston, A.L.S. 4p. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Rembrandt Peale, Philadelphia, Feb. 6, 1844; 7-1/2x5; Lewis, William D.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Resigns from board of managers of the museum.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Escol Sellers, New York, March 4, 1844; 9-3/4x8; Sellers, Charles, 1806-1898
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Machine business is very good, but needs someone to take over other practice.
  - Letters to Ann Sellers, March 25, May 31, 1844, 1865; Sellers, Nathan
    D. 53 items. Various sizes. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Family letters, with some poetry.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Sophonisba Peale] Sellers, Philadelphia, April 2, 1844; 10x8; Harrold, Alfred, d. 1845
    Birmingham, A.L.S. 4p.,add. Friendly letter. Family news. Refers to Rembrandt Peale.
  - Letter to Ann Sellers, Mill Bank, April 7, 1844; 10x8; Sellers, George Escol
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 4p.,add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Sophonisba Peale] Sellers, Philadelphia, April 17, 1844; 9x7; Harrold, Alfred, d. 1845
    London, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Hannah Sellers Hill], May 4, 1844; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
    Mill Bank, A.L. 2p. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Sophonisba Peale] Sellers, Philadelphia, June 2, 1844; 9x7-1/4; Harrold, Alfred, d. 1845
    London, A.L.S. 4p.,add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Sophonisba Peale] Sellers, Philadelphia, June 17, 1844; 9x7-1/4; Harrold, Alfred, d. 1845
    London, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Letter to [Mrs.] Hannah S[ellers] Hill, July 2, 1844; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
    Mill Bank, A.L. 3p.and add. Friendly letter. Concerning riots in Philadelphia.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Sophonisba Peale] Sellers, Philadelphia, July 13, 1844; 9x7-1/4; Harrold, Alfred, d. 1845
    Birmingham, A.L.S. 4p.,add. Friendly letter. Family news.